Register to the Papers of Kurt Weill and Lotte Lenya
Yale University Music Library
Register to the Papers of Kurt Weill and Lotte Lenya
1890-1984
MSS 30
Yale University Music Library
47
(107 boxes)
Music, correspondence and other papers, photographs, and additional materials by and about the German-American composer Kurt Weill (1900-1950) and the German-American actress and singer Lotte Lenya (1898-1981)
Weill, Kurt, 1900-1950
Conditions Governing Access
The Papers are open to researchers by appointment. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment. Some of the materials may be stored at the Library's off-campus shelving facility, so researchers should allow at least two business days to have the appropriate boxes paged.Permission to view certain correspondence must first be obtained from the Kurt Weill Foundation for Music, Inc., 7 East 20th Street, 3rd Floor, New York, NY 10003.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Papers of Kurt Weill and Lotte Lenya were established in the Music Library of Yale University by Lenya in 1981.
Arrangement
In 16 series as follows: I. Music by Weill. II. Arrangements for Lenya. III. Music by Others. IV. Correspondence. V. Programs. VI. Photographs. VII. Documents. VIII. Writings by Weill and Lenya. IX. Scripts and Lyrics for Works by Others. X. Interviews. XI. Biographical Items. XII. Financial Items. XIII. Loose Clippings. XIV. Clippings from Anna Krebs's Scrapbooks. XV. Miscellaneous Items. XVI. Kurt Weill Conference Items.
Scope and Contents
The Papers of Kurt Weill and Lotte Lenya contain manuscript scores and sketches of Weill's music, including American stage works as Down in the Valley, Lady in the Dark, One Touch of Venus, Street Scene, Lost in the Stars, Love Life, Firebrand of Florence, and Johnny Johnson. Music for stage works written in Germany includes the holograph scores for Happy End and Mahagonny-Songspiel. Photocopies of holograph scores for other works from his German period, including Die Dreigroschenoper and Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny, have been provided from the archives of Universal Edition, Vienna, which holds the original manuscripts. Other musical scores and sketches in the collection include the Cello Sonata, Symphony No. 1, String Quartet Op. 8, Quodlibet, Sinfonia Sacra, Frauentanz, Concerto for Violin and Wind Instruments, Das Berliner Requiem, Vom Tod im Wald, Symphony No. 2, You and Me, Railroads on Parade, Walt Whitman Songs, Where Do We Go From Here, A Flag Is Born, Weill's arrangement of the Israeli national anthem Hatikvah, and various arrangements of Weill's music for performances by Lenya after his death. Correspondence, programs, clippings, photographs, and personal documents belonging to Weill and Lenya comprise the remainder of the collection. The correspondence spans the entire careers of Weill and Lenya, and includes letters to and from their friends, families, and collaborators such as Georg Kaiser, Bertolt Brecht, Maxwell Anderson, Ira Gershwin, Ogden Nash, S.J. Perelman, and Langston Hughes. Photographs of Weill, Lenya, family, and friends, of musical productions by Weill, and of stage and film appearances by Lenya are included among the papers. The 20,000 clippings in the collection date from their early years in Berlin.
Biographical / Historical
Kurt Weill was born in Dessau, Germany on March 2, 1900. His father was a cantor and composer of Jewish sacred music, so Weill received musical training from an early age. He later studied with Humperdinck at the Berlin Musikhochschule for a year, but his most important composition teacher would prove to be Ferruccio Busoni, with whom he studied for several years in Berlin.
In the early phase of his career, Weill supported himself by working as a radio journalist and music teacher. (Maurice Abravanel and Claudio Arrau were numbered among his pupils.) Several of Weill's works were published and performed in this period, but he gained wider acclaim with his opera Der Protagonist(1926), with a libretto by Georg Kaiser. Weill and Kaiser also worked together on Der Zar lässt sich photographieren and Der Silbersee. Weill's most celebrated collaborator, however, was Bertolt Brecht, who wrote the texts for works such as Mahagonny Songspiel, Das Berliner Requiem, Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny, and Die sieben Todsünden. Their greatest success was Die Dreigroschenoper (1928), which caused an international sensation and made Weill financially secure. Although he specialized in music for the theater, Weill also composed instrumental works in the 1920s and '30s, including symphonies, string quartets, and a violin concerto.
As a left-leaning modernist intellectual of Jewish birth, Weill was an obvious target for Nazi hostility, and he fled to Paris shortly after Hitler's rise to power in 1933. In 1935 he moved to the United States, where he remained for the rest of his life. In America Weill composed numerous works for Broadway, ranging from the popular Knickerbocker Holiday, Lady in the Dark, and One Touch of Venus to the tragic Street Scene; he collaborated with a remarkable series of playwrights and lyricists including Ira Gershwin, Moss Hart, Langston Hughes, S.J. Perelman, and Ogden Nash. He also wrote four film scores. Several songs from Weill's dramatic works became popular hits, most notably "Die Moritat von Mackie Messer" (from Die Dreigroschenoper, and known in English as "Mack the Knife") and "September Song" (from Knickerbocker Holiday). Weill died in New York in 1950.
Karoline Wilhelmine Blamauer, who used the name Lotte Lenya, was born in Vienna in 1898. She began her career as a dancer in the Zurich ballet in 1914. In 1920 she moved to Berlin, where two years later, encouraged by Georg Kaiser, she became involved in the spoken theater. Kaiser also introduced Lenya to Weill, whom she married in 1926. She sang in the 1927 performance of Mahagonny-Songspiel at the Baden-Baden festival, and in 1928 she appeared as Jenny in Die Dreigroschenoper in Berlin, a role that won her international acclaim. Lenya appeared in three more of Weill's works during his lifetime: Die Sieben Todsünden, The Eternal Road, and The Firebrand of Florence. Weill and Lenya divorced in 1933 and remarried in 1937.
After Weill's death, Lenya devoted much of her time and energy to promoting and performing his music. The Threepenny Opera (Marc Blitzstein's English adaptation of Die Dreigroschenoper) was a resounding success on Broadway, and in 1956 Lenya won a Tony Award for her performance. Her activities were not limited to her husband's works, however, and she appeared in a number of other plays and films: Tennessee Williams' The Roman Spring of Mrs. Stone, Brecht on Brecht, the James Bond thriller From Russia with Love, the Broadway production of Cabaret, The Appointment, and Semi-Tough. She died in 1981.
Actresses -- Correspondence; Composers -- Correspondence; Music -- Germany -- 20th Century; Music -- United States -- 20th Century; Musicals; Operas; Le Corbusier, 1887-1965; Abravanel, Maurice, 1903-1993; Adorno, Theodor W., 1903-1969; Anderson, Maxwell, 1888-1959; Antheil, George, 1900-1959; Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), 1907-1973; Aufricht, Ernst-Josef; Behrman, S. N. (Samuel Nathaniel), 1893-1973; Bergman, Ingmar, 1918-2007; Berlin, Irving, 1888-1989; Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990; Blitzstein, Marc, 1905-1964; Brecht, Bertolt, 1898-1956; Busoni, Ferruccio, 1866-1924; Caniff, Milton Arthur, 1907-1988; Cocteau, Jean, 1889-1963; Coward, Noel, 1899-1973; Crawford, Cheryl, 1902-1986; De Mille, Agnes, 1905-1993; Deval, Jacques, 1890-1972; Dietrich, Marlene, 1901-1992; Downes, Olin, 1886-1955; Dreyfus, Max, 1874-1964; Ebert, Carl, 1887-1980; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955; Ernst, Max, 1891-1976; Fontanne, Lynn, 1887-1983; Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009; Gauty, Lys, 1908-1994; Gershwin, Ira, 1896-1983; Gordon, Max, 1903-1989; Green, Paul, 1894-1981; Hammarskjöld, Dag, 1905-1961; Hart, Moss, 1904-1961; Hayes, Helen, 1900-1993; Hellman, Lillian, 1905-1984; Henze, Hans Werner, 1926-2012; Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967; Huston, Walter, 1884-1950; Jacobi, Lotte, 1896-1990; Kaiser, Georg, 1878-1945; Kaufman, George S. (George Simon), 1889-1961; Korda, Alexander, Sir, 1893-1956; Koussevitzky, Serge, 1874-1951; Lawrence, Gertrude, 1952-; Lazar, Irving, 1907-1993; Leigh, Vivien, 1913-1967; Lenya, Lotte, 1898-1981; Lerner, Alan Jay, 1918-1986; Levine, James, 1943-; Levine, Maurice; Lieberson, Goddard, 1911-1977; Logan, Joshua, 1936-1987; Lunt, Alfred, 1892-1977; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982; Mamoulian, Rouben, 1897-1987; Mayer, Edwin Justus, 1896-1960; McArthur, Charles, 1920-; Meredith, Burgess, 1907-1997; Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974; Mitropoulos, Dimitri, 1896-1960; Nash, Ogden, 1902-1971; Neher, Caspar, 1897-1962; Paton, Alan, 1903-1988; Perelman, S. J. (Sidney Joseph), 1904-1979; Piscator, Erwin, 1893-1966; Reed, Rex; Reinhardt, Max, 1873-1943; Rice, Elmer, 1892-1967; Rodgers, Richard, 1902-1979; Rose, Billy, 1899-1966; Saroyan, William, 1908-1981; Sills, Beverly, 1929-2007; Sirmay, Albert, 1880-1967; Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977; Streisand, Barbra, 1942-; Sundgaard, Arnold, 1909-2006; Tabori, George, 1914-2007; Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989; Thurber, James, 1894-1961; Van Grove, Isaac; Van Loon, Gerard Willem, 1911-; Watt, Douglas, 1914-2009; Weigel, Helene, 1900-1971; Weill, Kurt, 1900-1950; Weisgal, Meyer Wolfe, 1894-1977; Weizmann, Chaim, 1874-1952; Werfel, Franz, 1890-1945; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975; Wouk, Herman, 1915-
- Music by Weill, 1913-1983; Series I; 23.3' (41 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  The Weill/Lenya Papers include holograph, manuscript, and published music by Weill, as well as Weill's arrangements of music by other composers. Copies of many holograph and manuscript scores from Universal Edition in Vienna, as well as a copy of Weill's arrangement of Hatikvah from the Hebrew University of Jerusalem, and sketches for Gustav III from O. W. Neighbour, are included.
  Twelve microfilms of several individual works had been made prior to the processing of the papers. The remainder of the music by Weill has been microfilmed also (15 reels). Items which were not filmed include duplicate copies of parts, photographic copies of items, and librettos and published music unless they contain manuscript markings. Reel and frame numbers for the items contained in the 15 reels are indicated in the register after the collation, for example, R.1, Fr.1-163. These reels are in the boxes indicated below: box 110: reels 1-6; box 111: reels 7-12; box 112: reels 13-15.
  The boxes are housed in the Assistant Librarian's office in the Music Library. A positive copyflo copy has been made from a microfilm of the full score of Der Zar lässt sich photographieren from Universal Edition. Master negatives of all the microfilms are housed in the Beinecke Library under the music deposit number 83.
  The provenance of a copy of any item from another source is noted in the description under the entry.
  Music by Weill is divided into nine subseries by genre. Letters are assigned to each of David Drew's genre divisions in The New Grove with the exception of the final subseries, "I," which contains unidentified sketches. The works are arranged alphabetically by title within each subseries. Uniform titles are used to bring together all of the manifestations of a work with various titles. Cross-references refer one from other forms of titles to the uniform titles. Cross-references have also been made between related works and for forms of a work such as sketches, which are found with another work.
  The titles for each work are arranged alphabetically without regard to punctuation:
  Dreigroschenoper
  Dreigroschenoper. Arie der Lucy
  Dreigroschenoper; arr. der Lucy
  Dreigroschenoper. Libretto. English
  Dreigroschenoper. Moritat vom Mackie Messer. Text
  Dreigroschenoper. Selections
  Dreigroschenoper. Tango-Ballade. Vocal score
  Dreigroschenoper. Vocal score
  The date or dates for a work appear in the first entry only, unless the item includes a date. The folders are numbered consecutively throughout the entire series. Oversize items are housed in boxes which are at the end of the entire collection, in order to save shelf space.
  - Operas, Operettas, Musicals, and Ballets, I.A
    - Alabama-Song
      General
      See: Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny. Nr. 2. Oh show us the way...
    - Anywhere
      See: Knickerbocker holiday. It never was you.
    - [Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny] Mahagonny, 1927 Apr-1929 Apr.; 1 score (449 sheets); 42 cm. (Box 101, Folder 1-3)
      Holograph signed (photocopy).
      Words by Bertolt Brecht.
      Copy of the original from Universal Edition (Wien).
      Acts II and III have identical title pages: "Aufstieg u. Fall der Stadt/Mahagonny/Oper in 3 Akten/von/Kurt Weill/Text/von/Bert Brecht/1. Akt/Partitur."
      "Pauke nicht lichtpausen auch die Streicher nicht, diese sind schon erschienen" - note on p. 1.
    - [Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny] Mahagonny., 10 parts; 32 cm. R. 1, Fr. 1-163. (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
      Manuscript in ink.
      Includes flute, clarinet I-II, soprano saxophone, alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet I-II, trombone, and banjo/guitar.
    - Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny. Denn wie man sich bettet
      See: Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny. Nr. 20. An einem grauen Vormittag.
    - [Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny. Libretto] Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny: Oper in drei Akten / von Bert Brecht; Musik von Kurt Weill., 49 sheets; 30 cm. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Typescript with page numbers in pencil.
      Note laid in p. 20.
    - [Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny. Libretto. English] Kurt Weill's The Rise and Fall of the City of Mahagonny / text by Bertolt Brecht; translated by Michael Feingold, 1973 Sep 1.; [66] p. in various pagings; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Typescript (photocopy).
      "Rough draft Act One - September 1, 19730 - title page.
    - Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny. Alabama-Song
    - [Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny. Nr. 2. Oh show us the way...] Alabama-Song: aus der Oper "Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny" / Kurt Weill; Spezialarrangement für Salonorchester mit Jazzstimmen von Richard Etlinger. - Wien: Universal Edition, c1930., 18 parts; 27 cm. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Arranged for flute, oboe, clarinet I-II, saxophone I-II, trumpet I-II, trombone, percussion, violin I, violin obbligato, viola, double bass, banjo, harmonium, and piano-conductor.
    - [Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny. Nr. 2. Oh show us the way... (Sketches)], [1] sheet of music; 42 cm. (Box 101, Folder 9)
      Holograph (photocopy).
      Copy of original sketch (crossed out) from Universal Edition (Wien).
      "UE 602" - upside down on top of p.
    - [Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny. Nr. 2. Oh show us the way... Text] Alabama-song., [2] sheets; 30 cm. R. 1, Fr. 164-165. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Typescript with ink additions.
    - [Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny. Nr. 2. Oh show us the way... Vocal score] Alabama-song: blues aus Mahagonny / Kurt Weill; Text von Bert Brecht. --Wien: Universal Edition, c1928., 1 vocal score (4 p.) 31 cm. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Pl. no.: U. E. 8900.
    - [Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny. Nr. 20. An einem grauen Vormittag...], 1 part; 32 cm. R. 1, Fr. 170-173. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Manuscript in ink with pencil markings.
      Piano part.
    - [Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny. Nr. 20. An einem grauen Vormittag...; arr.], [3] p. of music; 34 cm. R. 1, Fr. 166-169. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Holograph in pencil.
      An arrangement which David Drew notes was "commissioned by Bost Records Inc. for Lotte Lenya."
      No. 2 of Six Songs by Kurt Weill [David Drew].
      Text not included.
      With: Sketch for "Wooden wedding" from One Touch of Venus.
    - [Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny. Nr. 20. An einem grauen Vormittag... Text] Wie man sich bettet - so liegt man., [2] sheets; 28 cm. R. 1, Fr. 174-175. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - [Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny. Nr. 20. An einem grauen Vormittag... Text] Wie man sich bettet., [1] sheet; 27 cm. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Typescript.
    - [Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny (Sketches)], [5] p. of music; 34 cm. R. 1, Fr. 176-180. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Includes sketches identified by David Drew as being for nos. 1d/9b, 13, 19e, 19e/5d.
    - [Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny. Vocal score] Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny: Oper in drei Akten / Kurt Weill; Text von Brecht; Klavierauszug mit Text von Norbert Gingold. - Wien: Universal Edition, c1929., 1 vocal score (332 p.); 31 cm. R. 1, Fr. 181-349. (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Contains pencil additions by Weill and colored pencil additions in another hand.
      Pl. no.: Universal Edition Nr. 9851.
    - Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny. Wie man sich bettet - so liegt man
      See: Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt der Mahagonny. Nr. 20. An einem grauen Vormittag...
    - Ballad of Caesar
      See: Silbersee. Rom hiess eine Stadt.
    - Ballade von der Höllenlili
      See: Happy end. Höllenlili.
    - [Bürgschaft] Bürgschaft, 1931 Oct.; 1 score (367 p., sheets 1-151 [i.e. 518] sheets); 42 cm. (Box 102, Folder 15-17)
      Words by Caspar Neher and Weill from Der afrikanische Rechtspruch by Johann Gottfried v. Herder.
      Dates at end of Act I: 1931 Aug 6. - Act II: 1931 Sep 2. - Act III: 1931 Oct 19.
      Copy of original from Universal Edition (Wien).
    - [Bürgschaft. Vocal score (Sketches)], 1 vocal score ([126] p.); 34 cm. R. 1, Fr. 350-473. (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Contents: Vorspiel ([10] p.). - Act I: Nr. 4 ([40] p.). - Act II: Nr. 10 (36 p.). - Act III: (41 p.).
      "Final draft" - David Drew.
    - [Bürgschaft. Vocal score (Sketches)], [18] p. of music; 34 cm. R. 1, Fr. 474-491. (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Loose sheets.
    - Caesar ballad
      See: Silbersee. Rom hiess einer Stadt.
    - Come in, mornin'
      See: Huckleberry Finn. Come in, sun.
    - [Davy Crockett. Libretto], [1938].; [106] sheets in various pagings; 28 cm. R. 1, Fr. 492-601. (Box 2, Folder 19)
      Typescript with pencil additions.
      Text to an unfinished musical with words by H. R. Hays.
      Composed in 1938 Jan.-Apr. (David Drew].
    - [Davy Crockett (Sketches)], [2] p. of music; 34 cm. R. 1, Fr. 602-627 [all sketches]. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - [Davy Crockett (Sketches)], [6] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 20)
      Holographs in pencil.
      Includes sketches headed "Indian Battle," "Interscene 3," and "Beginning 1st scene."
    - [Davy Crockett (Sketches)], [20] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - [Davy Crockett (Sketches)], [11] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - [Davy Crockett. Vocal score] Davy Crockett / H. R. Hays and Kurt Weill., 1 vocal score ([49] p.); 32 cm. R. 1, Fr. 628-660. (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Holograph signed, in ink with pencil markings, words printed in ink in another hand.
      Contents: Act I: Introduction ([1] p.)."Oh I'm a rolling stone..." ([4] p.)."Where the green pines shadow the ground..." ([3] p.). Interscene 1 ([4] p.)."Davy what flickers and flames in your heart..." [Song of the trees] ([4] p.). Interscene 11 ([6] p.). Opening scene V [The hand is quicker than the eye] ([3] p.)."Dear Mr. Crockett..." [Letter song] [2] p.)."Watch out for me..." [6] p.). [March] [3] p.). Finale lst part (unfinished) [2] p.). Act II: Opening scene 8 ([2] p.)."Here follows Interscene IV (not finished)" [in Kurt Weill's hand at top of Opening scene 9 [All goes badly] ([2] p.)]."I can pass ray days alone..." [Time is standing still] [4] p.)."Here follows Battle of Alamo (not finished)" [in Kurt Weill's hand before pencil sketch at end ([2] p.)].
      Also on title page: Piano score (first, incomplete draft only for rehearsal purpose).
    - Denn wie man sich bettet
      See: Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny. Nr. 20. An einem grauen Vormittag...
    - Dependency ballad
      See: Dreigroschenoper. Ballade von der sexuellen Hörigkeit.
    - Deux chansons d'Yvette Guilbert
      See: Dreigroschenoper. Pauv' Madam' Peachum... Vocal score. French.
    - [Down in the valley] Down in the valley, 1945 Nov.; 1 score (119 sheets); 37 cm. R. 1, Fr. 661-722. (Box 2, Folder 22)
      Holograph in ink (in part, photocopies pasted on) with additions in pencil; words, voice lines, measure numbers, etc., in another hand in red ink; text is occasionally taped on (typescript).
      Words by Arnold Sundgaard.
      "[Folk-opera in one-act, mainly for nonprofessional production]."
    - Down in the valley / Kurt Weill [1945-1948]., 50 parts; 32 cm. R. 1, Fr. 723-963. R. 2, Fr. 1-10. (Box 2, Folder 23-27, Box 3, Folder 28)
      Manuscript in copyist's hand in ink [master copies on onionskin].
      For chorus (SATB) and orchestra.
      Chorus parts (original and 16 copies), flute I-II, oboe, clarinet I-II, bass clarinet, bassoon, horn I-II, trumpet I-II, trombone, percussion, guitar, harp, violin I (original and 4 copies), violin II (original and 3 copies), viola (original and 2 copies), violoncello (original and 2 copies), and double bass.
      "Old version" - on old folders.
    - [Down in the valley. Libretto] Down in the valley., 12 sheets; 28 cm. R. 2, Fr. 11-22. (Box 3, Folder 29)
      Typescript with pencil additions by Kurt Weill.
    - [Down in the valley (Sketches)], [1948 Apr.] [David Drew].; [17] p. of music; 34 cm. R. 2, Fr. 22-33. (Box 3, Folder 30)
      Sketches for later version.
    - [Down in the valley. Vocal score], 1 vocal score (56 p.); 32 cm. R. 2, Fr. 34-69. (Box 3, Folder 31)
      Holograph in ink with pencil additions.
      Reverse image master copy of the holograph score laid in.
    - Drei Heilsarmeelieder
      See: Happy end. Selections. Vocal score.
    - [Dreigroschenoper], 1928 Aug 23.; 1 score [101] sheets in various pagings); 42 cm. (Box 102A, Folder 32)
      Contents: Act I: Nr. 1. Ouvertüre (5 sheets). Nr. 2. Moritat vom Mackie Messer (4 sheets). Nr. 3. Morgenchorale des Peachum (sheet 6). Nr. 4. Anstatt dass-Song (sheets 7-11). Nr. 5. Hochzeitslied (sheets 12-13). Nr. 6. Seeräuberjenny (5 sheets). Nr 7. Kanonensong (sheets 19-22). Nr. 8. Liebeslied (sheets 23-25). Barbarasong ([3] sheets). Nr. 10. I. Dreigroschenfinale (10 sheets). - Act II: 11 [11a?]. Polly's Lied ([2] sheets). Nr. 11a [11?]. Melodram ([2] sheets). Nr. 12. Ballade von der sexuellen Hörigkeit ([4] sheets). Nr. 13. Zuhälterballade (8 sheets). 14. Ballade vom angenehmen Leben (6 sheets). - Act III.: Nr. 17. Lied von der Unzulänglichkeit menschlichen Strebens ([2] sheets). Nr. 18. Salomonsong ([2] sheets). 19. Ruf aus der Gruft (sheets 102-103). Nr. 20. Grabschrift ([4] sheets). 20a. Gang zu Galgen ([1] sheet). Nr. 21. III. Dreigroschenfinale (14 sheets). [Extra copy of first p. of Nr. 18 at end].
      Copy of original from Universal Edition (Wein).
      Does not include number 22.
      At end: 23. August 1928 Charlottenburg.
    - [Dreigroschenoper] Die Dreigroschenoper = The beggar's opera / Kurt Weill; nach dem Englischen des John Gay übersetzt von Elisabeth Hauptmann; Deutsche Bearbeitung von Bert Brecht. - [Wien: Universal Edition] c1928., 25 parts; 32 cm. R. 2, Fr. 70-307. (Box 3, Folder 33-39)
      For alto saxophone/flute/clarinet II, tenor saxophone/soprano saxophone/bassoon/clarinet II, trumpet I-II, trombone, double bass, percussion (2), banjo/guitar/bandoneon, violoncello, and harmonium (2).
      Pl. no.: Universal Edition No. 8849.
      Includes 17 published parts with manuscript corrections, and 8 partly or entirely manuscript parts in copyist's hand in ink.
    - [Dreigroschenoper. Arie der Lucy. Vocal score] Arie der Lucy: Dreigroschenoper / Kurt Weill; Text von Bert Brecht., 1 vocal score (6 p.); 34 cm. R. 2, Fr. 308-313. (Box 3, Folder 40)